KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi | Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

SUMMARY

Dedicated Front End Engineer & Developer with experience building Full-stack applications with functional UX/UI. Extensive customer service, technical training, and project management experience during my time at AT&T. Expertise in troubleshooting/debugging code, creative Responsive Web Design for Mobile App Development. I'm always going the extra mile according to customers who nominated me for company recognition for my outstanding service. I learned it's better to be pro-active than reactive from working on large scale projects. I love to learn new things as shown by my career path from Web Developer to Network Admin to Project Technical Manager.

TECHNICAL SKILL PROFICIENCY

Expert: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, APIs, Git/GitHub, Linux, Bash/Powershell, Bootstrap, Node.js, NPM, Webpack, SQL (NoSQL, MySQL), SASS, jQuery, Postman, Express, Agile Scrum, MS Office, Google Suite

Intermediate: MongoDB, React.js, Redux, Angular4+, TypeScript, AWS, Heroku, Jest, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development, Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ, Oct 2019
Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ

CERTIFICATIONS

Front-End Web Developer, Udacity

Six-Sigma Green Belt

Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA)

2015

2009

2004

PROJECTS

Advanced Property Management | Live Demo https://limitless-journey-49486.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack Developer utilizing the following stack: MongoDB, Express, React, Redux, Node
- Incorporated User Authentication for users to register and login by email and password utilizing JSON Web Tokens and saving user data into a Mongo database.
- Used Redux for state management of user data and authentication across all React components.

Common Ground | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds |

Live Demo https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds

- Backend Developer utilizing the following stack: JavaScript, AJAX, Firebase Real-time Database
- Incorporated User Authentication for users to register and login by email and password or social media login and stores login information along with profile information into a Firebase Real-time Database.

MeVite | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/MeVite | Live Demo https://mevite.herokuapp.com

- Backend Developer utilizing the following stack: MySQL, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Passport
- Incorporated Passport.js for user registration and authentication by saving user information in a Sequelize database.
- Configured the database to also save event information and contacts for tracking attendance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rutgers Division of Continuing Studies, Somerset, NJ Full Stack Web Developer Instructor, May 2019 – Present

Teaching in-person class on the MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node) including focus on the latest versions of JavaScript (including ES6), CSS, HTML, MySQL, and Git.

- Guided up to 20 30 students to develop projects and assisted them with problem-solving/troubleshooting issues
 on their projects. Worked 1:1 with students to understand key technological concepts in development which
 resulted in reduction of the class drop-out rate by 10-15%.
- Emphasized the management and versioning of the code using Git and GitHub. Demonstrated how to resolve any conflicts that occurred from merging code from different sources and coached them on best practices on how to prevent such conflicts.
- Completed cohorts exceeded career services post-graduation outcomes standards by 13.85%
- Created lesson summary documents for the Full Stack curriculum.

K. Renaldi - Resume Page 1 of 2

Technical Manager, Apr 2010 – May 2019

Subject matter expert on circuit ordering software and service. Led online training & onboarding meetings. Developed and updated training documentation. Worked on large scale projects for **Panera Bread** and **JC Penney**.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my projects activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% by having my team follow up with clients as to whether they want service or to cancel.
- Traveled to provide in-person training and coaching at domestic and overseas offices.
- Managed and coached a team of anywhere between 6 to 21 people depending on the product I was supporting.
- Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

Process Engineer, Sep 2008 - Apr 2010

Trained and coached new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service and circuit ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for new engineers. Worked closely with Software Engineering teams to test and develop new ordering software.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

Provisioning Technical Engineer, May 2000 - Sep 2008

Assisted clients with their circuit ordering, network design, and architecture in order for their networks to communicate over the AT&T backbone from their datacenter and performed performance management review and troubleshooting to ensure communication was up and stable.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance with an average of 98% (exceeding the target of 90-95%) and Cycle Time with an average of 28 days (shorter than the target of 30 days). As a result of my performance, my team exceeded the On-Time Performance target with a 96% average and Cycle Time of 29 days.
- Earned 7 Commitment to Excellence awards awarded by customers and sales account teams for providing outstanding customer service for several high-profile clients such as La-Z-Boy, Crown Castle, Office Depot, and Motel 6.
- Managed and completed up to 60 projects in a given month.

CMS Content Manager/QA Tester, Dec 1998 - May 2000

Wrote and updated technical documentation for publication on AT&T's internal Content Management System where the provisioning and technical support teams have a single resource to pull information on how to perform certain tasks. Performed QA tests on new software for documentation and feedback to the developers.

- Re-designed the layout and architecture of the site for easier search capabilities for end users.
- Set up and maintained UNIX Web Server for developing and testing web applications that employees used to make their job function easier.

K. Renaldi - Resume Page 2 of 2